thestage.co.uk 2015-09-06

# Privacy policy | The Stage

BY USING OUR WEBSITE YOU ACCEPT AND CONSENT TO THE COLLECTION, USE AND TRANSFER OF YOUR DATA IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY.

In this Privacy Policy, “we”, “us”, “our” or “The Stage” means The Stage Media Company Limited. For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act), we are registered with the ICO with notification number Z3499412.

We take the protection of the privacy of persons visiting the [www.thestage.co.uk](http://www.thestage.co.uk/) website (the “Website” “our site”) seriously. This Privacy Policy explains what information we will collect about you, how we will use that information and the steps that we will take to ensure that it is kept secure. By using the Website you consent to us collecting and using information about you in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Introduction and applicable terms

This Privacy Policy sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.

The Stage Castings is an online casting service made available to the general public including performers, advertisers and agents through our website and is operated by us (“The Stage Castings”). Please note that in addition to the general terms set out below the specific terms set out at [The Stage Castings](http://www.thestage.co.uk/terms/privacy/#privacy-0-0-castings) apply to the collection, use and transfer of your data submitted to or connected with your use of The Stage Castings. If there is any conflict or ambiguity between these general terms and the specific terms, the later will override the former.

### Why we collect your personal data

At the Website we collect different types of information about our users for three main reasons:

  1. To help us to improve the services we offer.
  2. To provide personalised services unique to individual users.
  3. To use anonymous details about our users to sell appropriate advertising space on the site. This might mean showing an advertiser how many users we have on the site; it does not mean sharing an individual’s details with an advertiser. Where we collect registration information from an individual, we will never share that individual’s information with a third party, including an advertiser, without that user’s explicit permission.

We may collect information from you when you seek to use the Website’s StageTalk forum or if you wish to subscribe to The Stage’s newspaper. The information we collect from you enables us to verify the identity of people posting messages on StageTalk, moderate StageTalk and prevent inappropriate messages being posted on StageTalk. It also allows us to process subscription requests for The Stage’s newspaper and validate subscriber access to restricted parts of the website.

Where you seek to subscribe to The Stage’s newspaper, we may ask you to supply us with your credit card details. Your credit card details will be passed via a secure site to The Stage’s subscription fulfilment service provider.

### Use of your personal data for marketing purposes

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will inform you (for example before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [**info@thestage.co.uk**](mailto:info@thestage.co.uk).

### Our principles

We are absolutely committed to protecting your privacy. Our policy can be summarised in one sentence:  **We will not share your information with others without your prior consent.**

**Notwithstanding the previous sentence** , please see below [paragraph 6](http://www.thestage.co.uk/terms/privacy/#privacy-6-0-puresolo) which sets out details of the disclosure to Pure Solo of your personal data as a consequence of you using the Pure Solo App, in circumstances where you access the Pure Solo App through The Stage Castings.

We have also established the following four guiding principles:

  1. We will continue to invest in high-quality security and do our utmost to protect user privacy through the appropriate use of the latest security technology.
  2. We will respect your email privacy. You will not receive unsolicited mail from The Stage and/or from third parties screened by The Stage Media Company Limited unless you have agreed to this. We will, however, mail you occasionally with information about your registration and/or your subscription account.
  3. We will not pass on any individual user details (including your email address) unless we have your prior consent.
  4. Otherwise, we will only share anonymous aggregate statistics about our users, sales and traffic patterns with our advertisers.

Should we elect to change our privacy policy we will post the changes here. Where the changes are significant, we may also choose to email all our registered users with the new details.

You have the right to request a copy of information about you that we hold, and to update such information and have any inaccuracies corrected. We will charge you a maximum of £10 for such requests. Please address such requests to us at [ **info@thestage.co.uk**](mailto:info@thestage.co.uk).

### What information do we collect?

We collect information on our users in two ways: through cookies, and through registration.

The minimum information we need to register a user is an email address, a password and a country. UK and US users will also need to provide a postcode/zipcode. We will ask further questions for different services, including competitions. Unless stated, all registration questions are compulsory. We also ask some further, voluntary questions so we can gain a clearer understanding of our users. Your responses help us to personalise services for our users. We do not share this information with third parties unless you have specifically consented to this.

We also collect data listing which of our pages are most frequently visited and by which types of users.

### How does thestage.co.uk protect customer information?

We invest in high-quality security and do our utmost to protect user privacy. UK Data Protection Legislation means we follow strict security procedures in the storage and disclosure of information that you have given us, to prevent unauthorised access.

### Will thestage.co.uk disclose the information it collects to outside parties?

thestage.co.uk will not sell, trade or rent your personal information to others unless you have given us your permission. With your permission we will only share the information with carefully chosen, reputable and trustworthy third parties. Also, thestage.co.uk may provide aggregate statistics about our customers, sales, traffic patterns and related site information to reputable third-party vendors, but these statistics will include no personally identifying information. thestage.co.uk follows the relevant legal requirements and uses all reasonable precautions to ensure only responsible third parties see the information, however we are not responsible for any breach of security or any actions of any third parties who receive the information.

Please note that we reserve the right to access and disclose individually identifiable information to comply with applicable laws and lawful government requests, to operate our systems properly, and to protect both our users and ourselves.

### Where we store your personal data

All information you provide to us is stored on third party platforms within the European Economic Area (“EEA”) and by submitting your personal data you consent to this transfer, storing and/or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy,

**Notwithstanding the foregoing** , certain data may be transferred outside of the EEA if you use the Pure Solo App through The Stage Castings. Please see below [paragraph 6](http://www.thestage.co.uk/terms/privacy/#privacy-6-0-puresolo) which sets out details of the disclosure to Pure Solo of your personal data as a consequence of you using the Pure Solo App, in circumstances where you access the Pure Solo App through The Stage Castings.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

### Legal information under the Data Protection Act and your rights

For the purposes of the Data Protection Act of 1998, the Data Controller for thestage.co.uk is The Stage Media Company Limited, Stage House, 47 Bermondsey Street, London SE1 3XT. Any queries regarding our use of data and data policies should be addressed to [ **info@thestage.co.uk**](mailto:info@thestage.co.uk) or write to the Managing Director at the above address.

Significant data processors for thestage.co.uk include Electronic Media Audit Limited, which from time to time may process server log data hosted by thestage.co.uk to independently audit site usage for ABCe certification.

From time to time, other parties may provide services on our behalf, using The Stage brand. The following third party services currently have their own privacy policy which you should read before you submit personal data to them:

  * [Booking.com](http://www.booking.com/general.en-gb.html?tmpl=docs/privacy-policy) provides hotel search and reservation systems
  * [Google](http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy.html) provides site searching and web searching facilities
  * Digital PC hosts the digital archive and online editions of The Stage newspaper.
  * Pure Solo provides a voice, dramatic and instrumental video recorder (please see [paragraph 6](http://www.thestage.co.uk/terms/privacy/#privacy-6-0-puresolo) for further information).

In addition, pages on our site may include content hosted on third party servers which may store additional information and/or request to store cookies within your web browser. Such usage is typically governed by the third parties’ own privacy and cookie policies. More information on this topic can be found within our separate [cookies policy](http://www.thestage.co.uk/terms/cookies/ "Cookie policy").

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites may have their own privacy and cookie policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

### Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy should be addressed to [**info@thestage.co.uk**](mailto:info@thestage.co.uk).

## THE STAGE CASTINGS

**IMPORTANT NOTICE ABOUT YOUR PERSONAL DATA** : Any information you post in public areas of The Stage Castings (for example in Performer Profiles, Advertiser Profiles, Agent Profiles or Available Castings) may be accessed, used and stored by others around the world, including countries that may not have legislation that guarantees adequate protection of personal information as defined by your country of residence. If you do not feel comfortable with this please do not post (or delete if already posted) information in the public areas of The Stage Castings.

Please see [The Stage Castings Terms of Use](http://castings.thestage.co.uk/terms) for the terms on which you may use The Stage Castings.

### 1\. Definitions

1.1. In this section the following definitions shall apply:

**“Advertiser Profile(s)”** means advertiser profiles set up by Advertisers which may include advertiser details such as contact information;

**“Advertiser(s)”** means advertisers (such as casting professionals and filmmakers) registered with a profile on The Stage Castings;

**“Agent Profile(s)** ” means agent profiles set up by Agents which may include agent details such as contact information;

**“Agent(s)”** means agents registered with a profile on The Stage Castings who represent performers (whether registered or not as a Performer on The Stage Castings);

**“Available Casting(s)”** means available castings posted by Advertisers which may include casting position details such as character description, remuneration and location;

**“Contributions”** means all contributions (including all information, images, photographs and videos) uploaded by you to The Stage Castings including in response to a Performer Profile, Advertiser Profile, Agent Profile or Available Casting;

**“Performer Profile(s)”** means performer profiles set up by Performers which may include performer details such as physical characteristics, experience, photos, videos and contact details;

**“Performer(s)”** performers registered with a profile on The Stage Castings (whether as a non-paying or paying subscriber);

**“Performer(s) (Full Member(s))”** means performers using The Stage Castings with a paid for subscription; and

**“Pure Solo”** and **“Pure Solo App”** have the meanings given in paragraph 6 below.

### 2\. Information we may collect from you when you use The Stage Castings

2.1. We may collect and process the following data about you:

2.1.1. information that you provide (such as Contributions or any information you provide when filling in forms);

2.1.2. information that you provide by completing a Performer Profile, for example:

2.1.2.1. photographs you upload (such as your headshots);

2.1.2.2. contact details (such as your email address, telephone number and address);

2.1.2.3. your characteristics and physical description (such as your date of birth, hair colour and other physical features);

2.1.2.4. experience and skills (such as previous jobs and language skills); and

2.1.2.5. your education details (such as qualifications and courses);

2.1.3. information that you provide by completing an Advertiser Profile or Agent Profile, for example contact details (such as your email address, telephone number and address);

2.1.4. if you are an Advertiser, information that you provide when completing an Available Casting;

2.1.5. if you are a Performer, information you provide when you make an application to an Available Casting;

2.1.6. if you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence / communication;

2.1.7. details of transactions you carry out through The Stage Castings; and

2.1.8. details of your visits to The Stage Castings including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access.

### 3\. Uses made of the information

3.1. We use information held about you in the following ways:

3.1.1. at your request, to create and host a profile for you (including a Performer Profile, Advertiser Profile or Agent Profile (as applicable)) on our site based on the information that you have provided to us;

3.1.2. at your request, to create and host an Available Casting for you on our site based on the information that you have provided to us;

3.1.3. if you use the Pure Solo App we will share your name and email address with Pure Solo and they will also have access to and will store and process your videos. Please see below [paragraph 6](http://www.thestage.co.uk/terms/privacy/#privacy-6-0-puresolo) which sets out details of the disclosure to Pure Solo of your personal data as a consequence of you using the Pure Solo App, in circumstances where you access the Pure Solo App through The Stage Castings;

3.1.4. to provide you with information about The Stage Castings that you may be interested in (such as emails setting out Available Castings (if you are a Performer or Agent));

3.1.5. Performer Profiles (Full Members) will be included in our Performer Directory which is a searchable online database and may be accessed and used by all users of The Stage Castings (including the general public);

3.1.6. to provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes; and

3.1.7. to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.

3.2. We will randomly select headshots from Performer Profiles to display on The Stage Castings website.

3.3. From time to time we may wish to use your Contributions (including videos) for advertising purposes. If we wish to do this we will contact you directly to ask for your permission for such use.

### 4\. Disclosure of your information

4.1. A key purpose of The Stage Castings is to provide the general public (including performers, advertisers and agents) a platform to broadcast and receive information. For this purpose, through your use of The Stage Castings, you, as a Performer, will share your information through your Performer Profile:

4.1.1. where your Performer Profile is listed in the Performer Directory, with all users of The Stage Castings; and

4.1.2. with Advertisers when you apply for an Available Casting.

4.2. A Performer may select, during the registration process and on the “Edit My Profile” page, whether his/her mobile number, landline number and email address is visible to other users of The Stage Castings. If a Performer selects not to make this contact information visible then the only time such information will be displayed is to an Advertiser where that Performer has submitted an application to an Available Casting posted by that Advertiser.

4.3. The visibility of a Performer Profile is set out below:

  * **Performer (Full Member):**
    * Listed and searchable in the Performer Directory.
    * Performer Profile can be seen by all users of the Site (including the general public) except the contact details which are subject to specific settings as noted in paragraph 4.2.
  * **Performer (Basic Member):**
    * Not listed in Performer Directory.
    * Contact information provided in the Performer Profile will only be visible to Advertisers where that Performer has made an application to that Advertiser.

4.4. Advertiser Profiles and Agent Profiles will not be visible to general users of The Stage Castings (including Performers). Contact details provided by Advertisers and Agents will not be made available on The Stage Castings.

4.5. We are unable to control how other users (including the general public) use your data.

4.6. You acknowledge and accept that, once you have made an application for an Available Casting your application cannot be withdrawn.

### 5\. Deleting a Performer Profile, Advertiser Profile or Agent Profile

5.1. You may delete your Performer Profile, Advertiser Profile or Agent Profile by emailing us at [castingshelp@thestage.co.uk](mailto:castingshelp@thestage.co.uk).

5.2. It may take up to one month to delete a profile and some information may remain in backup copies and logs for a reasonable period of time.

5.3. On deletion your profile will be permanently deleted and cannot be reactivated.

### 6\. Pure Solo

6.1. The Stage Castings makes available to Performers (Full Members) an application provided by Pure Solo Limited, a registered company in England and Wales with registration number 06107958, who have their registered office at 12 Melcombe Place, London NW1 6JJ (“Pure Solo” and the “Pure Solo App”). The Pure Solo App allows Performers (Full Members) to record voice, dramatic and instrumental content videos. In addition to this Privacy Policy, [the Pure Solo Privacy Policy](https://www.puresolo.com/privacy) applies to your use of the Pure Solo App.

6.2. If you access the Pure Solo App through The Stage Castings you will be sharing with Pure Solo the personal information you submit through your use of the Pure Solo App via The Stage Castings. Pure Solo will access, use and store such information in accordance with [the Pure Solo Privacy Policy](https://www.puresolo.com/privacy). They will also be given by us details of your name and email address and they will also have access to and will store, use and process your videos in accordance with [the Pure Solo Privacy Policy](https://www.puresolo.com/privacy). Please note that Pure Solo are an independent company and we do not control Pure Solo. Please also note that Pure Solo may transfer your personal data/information outside of the EEA. If you do not feel comfortable with any of this please do not use the Pure Solo App.

6.3. When, as a Performer (Full Member), you submit a video via the Pure Solo App through The Stage Castings you will have three options in relation to the visibility of that video: (a) visible only as part of the application for the Available Casting for which you are applying; (b) visible as part of that application and on your Performer Profile (which will be visible to all users of The Stage Castings including the general public); and (c) visible as part of that application and on your Performer Profile (which will be visible to all users of The Stage Castings including the general public) and visible in the ‘Showcase section’ of our site (which will be visible to all users of The Stage Castings including the general public). Please carefully select the option which you wish to apply.

6.4. For the avoidance of doubt, videos submitted via the Pure Solo App cannot be edited. If you wish to remove from The Stage Castings video content that you have submitted you must contact us at [castingshelp@thestage.co.uk](mailto:castingshelp@thestage.co.uk).

6.5. Alternatively, please note that you may select to sign-up directly with Pure Solo and not via The Stage Castings. As noted above, if you follow a link to any third party website, these websites may have their own privacy policies and we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these third party websites.
